Guide to the Porter Advertising Billboard Sketches, 1950s-1970s
The John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Porter Advertising Billboard Sketches 1950s-1970s
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Porter Advertising.
7 Linear Feet 200 Items
Porter Advertising, founded in 1945, is an out-of-home advertising company based in Richmond, Indiana.
Porter Advertising Billboard Sketches date between the 1950s and 1970s and document the company's poster designs for a wide range of businesses in the region around Richmond, Indiana. The collection includes rough and developed sketches; design drawings for specific businesses and campaigns; generic designs; and billboard mockups for local businesses such as car dealerships; banks and financial institutions; funeral homes; hospitals and clinics; motels; retail stores; restaurants; and others. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Porter Advertising Billboard Sketches were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2008.
Collection Overview
Porter Advertising Billboard Sketches date between the 1950s and 1970s and document the company's poster designs for a wide range of businesses in the region around Richmond, Indiana. The collection includes rough and developed sketches; design drawings for specific businesses and campaigns; generic designs; and billboard mockups for local businesses such as car dealerships; banks and financial institutions; funeral homes; hospitals and clinics; motels; retail stores; restaurants; and others.
Collection Arrangement
The collection is arranged alphabetically by product or service category and by business name.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Porter Advertising (Firm)
Advertising -- Automobiles -- United States
Advertising -- Banks and banking -- United States
Advertising -- Hospitals -- United States
Advertising -- Hotels -- United States
Advertising -- Restaurants -- United States
Advertising -- United States
Advertising, Outdoor
Advertising, Outdoor -- Indiana
Advertising, Outdoor -- United States
Advertising agencies
Advertising agencies -- Indiana
Advertising agencies -- United States
Advertising, Outdoor -- Indiana -- History
Advertising, Outdoor -- United States
Advertising, Outdoor -- United States -- History -- 20th century
Billboards -- Indiana
Billboards -- Indiana -- History
Billboards -- United States
Billboards -- United States -- History
Funeral Homes -- United States
Design drawings
Mock-ups
Design developmental drawings
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
Related Material
Materials related to this collection may be found in the following collections:
C&U Poster Advertising Company Records
Duplex Advertising Company Billboard Images and Records
Ohio Outdoor Advertising Corporation Records
Outdoor Advertising Association of America Poster Designs
R.C. Maxwell Company Records
Strobridge Lithographing Company Advertisements
Wilkins Media Corporation Records
Robert A. Hamer Papers
John Paver Papers
Contents of Collection
- Porter Outdoor Poster Designs, 1950s-1970s, (7 boxes)
  - Automotive A-Z, 1950s-1970s, (3 folders) (Box 1)
  - Banking A-D, 1950s-1970s, (2 folders)
  - Banking F, 1950s-1970s, (4 folders) (Box 2)
  - Banking F-W, 1950s-1970s, (5 folders) (Box 3)
  - Events, 1950s-1970s (Box 4)
  - Finance, 1950s-1970s
  - Funeral and mortuary services, 1950s-1970s, (2 folders)
  - Furniture and appliances, 1950s-1970s (Box 5)
  - Grocery, 1950s-1970s
  - Health industry, 1950s-1970s
  - Hotel and motel, 1950s-1970s
  - House and garden supplies, 1950s-1970s (Box 6)
  - Insurance, 1950s-1970s
  - Office supplies, 1950s-1970s
  - Political, 1950s-1970s, (2 folders) (Box 7)
  - Real Estate, 1950s-1970s
  - Religion, 1950s-1970s
  - Restaurants, 1950s-1970s
  - Retail, 1950s-1970s
  - Miscellaneous poster designs, 1950s-1970s